chartmogul.com 2019-04-29

# Privacy Policy | ChartMogul

All collection, processing and use (hereafter “usage”) of data by ChartMogul is exclusively for the purposes of providing the ChartMogul services (hereafter “services”). The services have been designed with the goal of collecting as little personal data as possible to function. By “personal data”, we mean all particulars related to an identified or identifiable natural person (the “data subject”).

The following statements describe which types of data we collect when you use our services, what happens with this data, and how you can object to this data processing, where applicable.

## Responsible Entities

For the purposes of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679, the responsible entity is:

ChartMogul CMTDE GmbH & Co. KG  
Oberwallstr. 6  
10117 Berlin  
Germany

General Partner of ChartMogul CMTDE GmbH & Co. KG:  
ChartMogul Management GmbH  
Oberwallstraße 6  
10117 Berlin

Managing directors of ChartMogul Management GmbH: Nicholas Franklin, Ingmar Zahorsky, Martin Raißle

## Appointed Data Protection Officer for the German branch office

The appointed data protection officer is:

ePrivacy GmbH

Große Bleichen 21  
20354 Hamburg  
Germany

For questions related to data protection, you can contact the appointed data protection officer via email through:

Or by post:

ePrivacy GmbH

Große Bleichen 21  
20354 Hamburg  
Germany

## Definitions

“Our Website(s)” and “ChartMogul Websites” refers to any website owned and / or operated by ChartMogul Ltd (as listed above), especially chartmogul.com (including all subdomains) and mogul.io (including all subdomains).

“ChartMogul Application” refers to ChartMogul’s product hosted at app.chartmogul.com.

## What Data we Collect

When you visit our website, our server temporarily saves details of your access in its logs. These logs contain the following data, and are kept until their automatic deletion:

  * The IP address of the computer making the request

  * The date and time of your request

  * The requested URI

  * The amount of data transferred to you in response

  * Whether the request was successfully processed or not

  * Identifying data about the browser and operating system you use

  * The referring website from which you made the request

  * The name of your Internet Service Provider

The purpose of recording this data is to make it possible to serve the website to you (by establishing a TCP/IP connection), to secure our servers, the technical administration of our infrastructure as well as the optimisation of our services. Only in the case of unauthorised access or attacks on our infrastructure will your IP address be analysed.

No further information is required from you in order to access our website.

## Securing your Data

In order to secure your data we have put in place technical and organisational measures which meet the requirements of the GDPR, and require any third-party service providers we use to do the same.

When we use third parties to provide the services, for example email and infrastructure service providers, these third parties are only engaged after a comprehensive review. This review carefully considers each third party’s competence as well as their technical and organisational data protection measures. The results of this review are recorded in writing, and a data processing agreement which is compliant with Article 28 of the GDPR is signed with the third party.

Your data is only ever saved on secure servers, which may only be accessed by a few authorised personnel. When you use a form on our website to transmit data to us, this transmission is only performed over an encrypted TLS connection.

## Third-Party Service Providers in non-EEA Countries

In order to provide our services, we use third-party services located outside the European Economic Area. To protect your personal data in this case, we have signed special data processing agreements with these service providers.

We use the following third-party service providers:

  * Service providers which ChartMogul Ltd uses to send emails

  * Service providers who offer server storage.

## Use of Cookies

  1. In addition to the previously listed data, cookies will be saved on your computer when you use our website. Cookies are small pieces of textual data which are saved on your hard disk by your web browser, through which ChartMogul, who sets the cookie’s contents, can collect certain information about you. Cookies cannot execute any code, nor transfer any viruses to your computer. We use them in order to anonymously or pseudonymously analyse the use of the website, and present relevant offers to you.

This website uses the following types of cookies, whose scope and functionality is detailed in the following paragraphs.

  * transient cookies (see paragraph 2)
  * persistent cookies (see paragraph 3)

  1. Transient cookies are automatically deleted when you close your browser. They are used particularly as session cookies. These save a so-called “session ID” which is used to link subsequent requests made by your browser to each other. Through this, your computer can be recognised when you return to our website. These session cookies are deleted, when you log out, or close your browser.

  2. Persistent cookies are only deleted after a predetermined duration, which can be different for each cookie. You can delete these persistent cookies anytime, though the “Settings” configuration of your browser. We advise you, that if you do so, that not all functionality of this website will be available.

The placement of cookies on your computer can be prevented through the relevant settings of your internet browser. Previously set cookies can also be deleted through the settings of your browser. We advise you that preventing the placement of cookies on your computer can mean that not all functionality of our website are available without limitations.

## Website Registration

The data subject can register on the website. For this to take place, it is required that the data subject enter their details in the “Sign Up” form. The data given by the data subject to register will solely be used for registration, and not passed to any third parties unless ChartMogul has a lawful ground to do so. . In the course of registration on our website, your IP address, date and time of access will be recorded, in order to prevent any potential misuse. During, or after the registration, the data subject is free to alter their personal data. It is also possible for the data subject to completely cancel their registration, so that all personal data is deleted.

## Data Protection for Job Applicants

It is possible to apply for jobs at ChartMogul through our online application system hosted by Recruitee (see details below). When you do so, we will process the personal data you send us, and save it in order to continue the application process.

If the application leads to an employment relationship, the supplied personal data will be retained, respecting the requirements of relevant law. Should the application not lead to an offer of employment, the personal data of the applicant will be deleted in accordance with our data retention policy, except when required to comply with §22 of the Allgemeines Gleichbehandlungsgesetz.

## Recruitee

ChartMogul uses Recruitee to advertise open positions at ChartMogul, receive applications to these positions and manage and optimise the application process.

The responsible entity is:

Recruitee B.V., Johan Huizingalaan 763A, 1066VH, Amsterdam, Netherlands

The hosting of job description and the application form is made possible through the use of JavaScript and cookies.

Information that the applicant provides when choosing to apply for an open postion, including personally identifiable information, like name & email address, mailing address, phone number and employment history; as well as the content of the application, is transferred to Recruitee’s servers and saved there.

Other information obtained via the cookies and / or the JavaScript widget is transferred to Recruitee’s servers and saved there.

The analyses of your actions on our Career website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Recruitee may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Recruitee.

You can find further information about Recruitee’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://recruitee.com/en/privacy>

Disqus provides the infrastructure for comments in ChartMogul’s blog.

The responsible entity is:

Disqus, Inc., 717 Market St, San Francisco, CA 94103 USA

The blog comment hosting services is made possible through the use of JavaScript, cookies and clear gifs.

Information that the user provides when choosing to register for or log into Disqus, or submit a comment, including personally identifiable information, like name & email address, as well as the content of the comment, is transferred to Disqus’ servers located in the United States, and saved there.

Other information obtained via the cookies, JavaScript widget, and / or the clear gifs is transferred to Disqus’ servers located in the United States, and saved there.

The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Disqus may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Disqus. Disqus also uses this information to provide targeted advertising to the user.

Users that have a Disqus account can update the privacy settings in their account to opt out of targeted advertising. Users that do not have a Disqus account can opt out of targeted advertising by visiting <https://disqus.com/data-sharing-settings/>

You can find further information about Disqus’ data processing and data protection at:

<https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy>

## Zendesk

ChartMogul uses Zendesk. This is a customer service platform provided by Zendesk, Inc. and enables us to provide support to our customers and users by a) offering help desk articles online, and b) offering means to contact ChartMogul.

The responsible entity is:

Zendesk, Inc., 1019 Market Street, 6th Floor, San Francisco, California 94103 USA

  1. Helpdesk Articles

Access to helpdesk articles is provided using a dedicated website, a JavaScript widget embedded on ChartMogul’s website (Zendesk Webwidget), and the use of cookies. Information obtained via these cookies and / or the JavaScript widget is transferred to Zendesk’s servers located in the United States, and saved there. The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Zendesk may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Zendesk.

  1. Contacting ChartMogul

If a user chooses to contact ChartMogul, either by emailing [help@chartmogul.com](mailto:help@chartmogul.com), [support@chartmogul.com](mailto:support@chartmogul.com), or any other email address associated with our Zendesk account; or by submitting a ticket through the contact form on our website or the Zendesk Webwidget, the content that the user chooses to submit is transferred to Zendesk’s servers located in the United States, and saved there. The content and metadata of your messages are submitted by Zendesk to ChartMogul. Zendesk may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Zendesk.

You can find further information about Zendesk’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/>

## Intercom

ChartMogul uses Intercom to notify users of new features in our product. We also use Intercom to manage information about our customers and leads.

The responsible entity is:

Intercom R&D Unlimited Company,

2nd Floor, Stephen Court,

18-21 St. Stephen’s Green,

Dublin 2, Republic of Ireland

Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, phone number and location & country is submitted to Intercom’s servers and saved there when a user chooses to sign up to the ChartMogul Application, to sign up for an event hosted or sponsored by ChartMogul, or to subscribe to notifications about new product features and other information from ChartMogul.

The option to subscribe to notification is made possible through the use of JavaScript and cookies. Information obtained via the cookies and / or the JavaScript widget, including IP address, browser version, OS version, activity data, usage information, transaction information and plan details is transferred to Intercom’s servers and saved there.

Other information, including IP address, browser & OS version, and timestamps, is submitted to Intercom when a user loads resources embedded in, or a link contained an email sent through Intercom.

The analyses of your actions on our website and with the notifications sent through Intercom is transferred to us in the form of reports. Intercom may give any of your information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Intercom.

You can find further information about Intercom’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy>

## Close.io

ChartMogul uses close.io to manage information about, and communicate with our customers and leads.

The responsible entity is:

Elastic Inc., PO Box 7775 #69574, San Francisco, CA 94120

Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, company name, and any other information contained in the user’s submission is transferred to Close.io’s servers and stored there when a user chooses to sign up for the ChartMogul Application, or contact ChartMogul’s Customer Success or Sales department.

Other information, including plan name & signup date is submitted to close.io when a user chooses to sign up for or use the ChartMogul Application.

Other information, including IP address, browser & OS version, and timestamps, is submitted to Close.io when a user loads resources embedded in, or a link contained an email sent through Close.io.

The analyses of your actions with the messages sent through Close.io is transferred to us in the form of reports. The content and metadata of your messages sent to ChartMogul’s Customer Success or Sales department are submitted by Close.io to ChartMogul. Close.io may give any of your information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Close.io.

You can find further information about Close.io’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/87166246>

## Mailchimp

ChartMogul uses Mailchimp to send newsletters to subscribers.

The responsible entity is:

The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA

Personally identifiable information, including name & email address is submitted to Mailchimp’s servers and saved there when a user chooses to sign up to the ChartMogul Application, or chooses to subscribe to one of ChartMogul’s newsletters.

Other information, including IP address, browser & OS version, and timestamps, is submitted to Mailchimp when a user loads resources embedded in, or a link contained an email sent through Mailchimp.

The analyses of your actions with the messages sent through Mailchimp is transferred to us in the form of reports. Mailchimp may give any of your information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Mailchimp.

You can find further information about Mailchimp’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/>

## Facebook

ChartMogul has integrated Facebook into its website.

The responsible entity for Facebook is:

Facebook, Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, United States.

When a data subject lives outside the United States or Canada, and Facebook undertakes data processing, the responsible entity is:

Facebook Ireland Ltd, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland

When a user clicks the Facebook button, Facebook’s website will be contacted, and user acquisition data will be transferred from ChartMogul to Facebook. Facebook will receive through this the information that the user has visited ChartMogul’s website. Details of the Facebook-supplied plugins can be accessed at:

<https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins>

If the user is logged into a Facebook account (even if it is not their own account) at the same time that they access they ChartMogul website, Facebook will additionally receive a notification that they have visited ChartMogul’s website. Facebook collects this information, so the theoretical possibility exists that it could associate it with the Facebook account. The same also applies to the “Like” button, or to the usage of Facebook comment forms; Facebook could associate this information with the logged-in Facebook account.

To prevent this, you can log out of any Facebook accounts prior to visiting the ChartMogul website. To do this, you must visit the Facebook website.

For further information relating to data protection and Facebook, please see:

<https://facebook.com/about/privacy>

## Twitter

ChartMogul uses Twitter.

The responsible entity is:

Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, United States

When a user clicks the Twitter button, Twitter will be contacted, and user acquisition data will be transferred from ChartMogul to Facebook. Twitter will receive through this the information that the user has visited ChartMogul’s website.

If the user is logged into a Twitter account (even if it is not their own account) at the same time that they access they ChartMogul website, Twitter will additionally receive a notification that they have visited ChartMogul’s website. Twitter collects this information, so the theoretical possibility exists that it could associate it with the Twitter account.

To prevent this, you can log out of any Twitter accounts prior to visiting the ChartMogul website. To do this, you must visit the Twitter website.

For further information relating to data protection and Twitter, please see:

<https://twitter.com/en/privacy>.

## LinkedIn

ChartMogul uses LinkedIn on its website.

The responsible entity for LinkedIn is:

LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA

If the user is logged into a LinkedIn account (even if it is not their own account) at the same time that they access the ChartMogul website, LinkedIn will additionally receive a notification that they have visited ChartMogul’s website. LinkedIn collects this information, so the theoretical possibility exists that it could associate it with the LinkedIn account.

To prevent this, you can log out of any LinkedIn accounts prior to visiting the ChartMogul website. To do this, you must visit the LinkedIn website.

For further information relating to data protection and LinkedIn, please see:

<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

## Google AdSense

ChartMogul uses Google AdSense, a service provided by Google Inc that enables us to advertise to previous visitors of our website and allows us to track the effectiveness of these ads.

The responsible entity is:

Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA, 94043, United States

The display of ads and measurement of their effectiveness is made possible through the use of cookies and clear gifs. Information obtained via these cookies and / or clear gifs is transferred to Google servers located in the United States, and saved there. The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Google may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Google.

You may opt-out of targeted advertising through Google AdSense by visiting: <https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/>

You can find further information about Google’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://policies.google.com/>

## Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics. This is a service of Google Inc (hereafter “Google”) which analyses website access, and enables us to improve our site.

The responsible entity is:

Google Inc, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA, 94043, United States

The analysis of your use of our website is made possible through the use of cookies. Information obtained via these cookies is transferred to Google servers located in the United States, and saved there. The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Google may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Google. The Google tracking on our website uses the “anonymizeIp()” function, which truncates the transmitted IP addresses so as to prevent the direct identification of any individual users.

You can stop the placement of Google Analytics cookies on your computer through the settings of your web browser. If you do so, we cannot guarantee that all the functions of our website will be fully available to you. You may also stop the placement of cookies through the use of browser extensions, such as:

You can find further information about Google’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://policies.google.com/>

And

<https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/>

## Stripe

ChartMogul Ltd uses Stripe to process payments for some of our existing customers and provide billing information to these customers.

The responsible entity is:

Stripe, Inc  
185 Berry Street,  
Suite 550,  
San Francisco, CA 94107

For those existing customers who are billed with Stripe or Recurly, the following data is sent, and stored by Stripe:

If you sign up to a paid ChartMogul subscription, the following data will be sent to Stripe, and saved by them:

  * Your name and email address

  * Details of your payment method (credit card number, expiry date, CVC)

  * Your IP address, and the time and date of your transaction

If you wish to avoid sending your data to Stripe, you can do so by not signing up for a paid ChartMogul plan. If you do so however, your ability to use ChartMogul’s functions could be severely reduced.

You may find further information about Stripe’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://stripe.com/us/privacy>

## Braintree

ChartMogul Ltd uses Braintree to process payments for some of our existing customers and provide billing information to these customers.

The responsible entity is:

Braintree  
PayPal (Europe) S.à r. l. et Cie, S.C.A,  
22-24 Boulevard Royal,  
L-2449, Luxembourg

For those existing customers who are billed with Braintree, the following data is sent, and stored by them:

  * Your name and email address

  * Details of your payment method (credit card number, expiry date, CVC)

  * Your IP address, and the time and date of your transaction

If you wish to avoid sending your data to Braintree, you may contact [support@chartmogul.com](mailto:support@chartmogul.com), and request to be billed on one of our current plans through Recurly. Please note that we cannot honor existing plans should you do so, and you will be migrated to the appropriate current plan. This may cost more.

Alternatively, you may cancel your ChartMogul account.

You may find further information about Braintree’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://www.braintreepayments.com/en-de/legal/braintree-privacy-policy>

## Recurly

ChartMogul Ltd uses Recurly to process payments from our customers and provide billing information to these customers.

The responsible entity is:

Recurly, Inc.  
400 Alabama St, Suite 202  
San Francisco, California 94110

If you sign up to a paid ChartMogul subscription, the following data will be sent to Recurly, and saved by them:

  * Your name and email address

  * Details of your payment method (credit card number, expiry date, CVC)

  * Your IP address, and the time and date of your transaction

If you wish to avoid sending your data to Recurly, you can do so by not signing up for a paid ChartMogul plan. If you do so however, your ability to use ChartMogul’s functions could be severely reduced.

You may find further information about Recurly’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://recurly.com/legal/privacy>

## Perfect Audience

ChartMogul uses Perfect Audience. This is a service provided by Marin Software Incorporated that enables us to advertise to previous visitors of our website and allows us to track the effectiveness of these ads.

The responsible entity is:

Marin Software Incorporated, 123 Mission Street, 27th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105 USA

The analysis of your use of our website and retargeting with ads is made possible through the use of cookies and clear gifs. Information obtained via these cookies and / or clear gifs is transferred to Perfect Audience’s servers located in the United States, and saved there. The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports. Perfect Audience may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Perfect Audience.

You can stop the placement of Perfect Audience cookies on your computer through the settings of your web browser. If you do so, we cannot guarantee that all the functions of our website will be fully available to you.

You may also opt-out of targeted advertising through Perfect Audience by visiting Perfect Audience’s Privacy Policy referenced below and following the instructions outlined there.

You can find further information about Perfect Audience’s data processing and data protection at:

<https://www.perfectaudience.com/privacy/>

## Eventbrite

ChartMogul uses Eventbrite to manage registrations to events hosted or sponsored by ChartMogul.

The responsible entity is:

Eventbrite, Inc. 155 5th Street, Floor 7, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA

Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, job title & company name is submitted to Eventbrite’s servers located in the United States, and saved there when a user chooses to sign up for an event hosted or sponsored by ChartMogul.

The option to subscribe to events is made possible through the use of cookies and JavaScript widgets. Information obtained via these cookies and / or JavaScript widgets is transferred to Eventbrite’s servers located in the United States, and saved there. The analyses of your actions on our website is transferred to us in the form of reports.

Eventbrite may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Eventbrite.

You may find further information about Eventbrite’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://www.eventbrite.com/support/articles/en_US/Troubleshooting/eventbrite-privacy-policy?lg=en_US>

## Typeform

ChartMogul uses Typeform to collect customer feedback in NPS surveys.

The responsible entity is:

TYPEFORM S.L., Carrer Bac de Roda, 163, 08018 Barcelona, Spain

Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, company name & country; and other information, including plan details and sign up data, is submitted to Typeform’s servers, and saved there when a user chooses to follow a link to a NPS survey.

The user’s responses to the survey, including service rating and comments, are submitted to Typeform’s servers and saved there when a user submits the survey.

Typeform may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Typeform.

You may find further information about Eventbrite’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://admin.typeform.com/to/dwk6gt>

## Advocate.ly

ChartMogul uses Advocate.ly to collect and follow up on customer feedback in NPS surveys.

The responsible entity is:

Advocately Inc., 2711 Centerville Road, Suite 400, Wilmington, Delaware, 19808, USA

Personally identifiable information, including name, email address, company name & country; and other information, including plan details, sign up data, service rating and comments, is submitted to Advocate.ly’s servers located in the United States, and saved there when a user chooses to submit responses to a NPS survey.

Advocate.ly may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Advocate.ly.

You may find further information about Advocate.ly’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://www.advocate.ly/privacy/>

## Zapier

ChartMogul uses Zapier to connect and share data between multiple web services used by ChartMogul.

The responsible entity is:

Zapier, Inc., 548 Market St. #62411, San Francisco, CA 94104-5401

Any information, including Personally identifiable information, collected by any other service listed in this privacy policy, may be submitted to Zapier’s servers, located in the United States, and saved there when a user takes an action that results in the submission of information to the original service. Zapier may give this information to further parties where legally required to do so, or these parties are contracted to by Zapier.

You may find further information about Zapier’s data processing and data protection here:

<https://zapier.com/privacy/>

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

ChartMogul reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time without notice. Any changes are effective when we post the updated Policy on our website. We recommend that you regularly check back. We may provide you with notices about changes to this Privacy Policy if you are a registered user of the ChartMogul Application.

Should you have further questions, or wish to make contact with us, you can do so though our website at www.chartmogul.com. When you do so, the data required to answer your query will be automatically saved and processed. Your data will not be transferred to third parties unless ChartMogul has a lawful ground to do so..

## Deletion of Personal Data

ChartMogul Ltd only keeps and processes personal data for so long as it is necessary. When the purpose of the data processing has been fulfilled, your personal data will be deleted in accordance with our data retention policy, unless we are legally required to retain it.

## Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data

In order to process personal data, a lawful ground must exist. A number of permitted grounds for processing are enumerated in Article 6 of the GDPR.

One ground for the processing of personal data is Article 6, Paragraph 1(a) of the GDPR, which is the freely given consent of the data subject to do so. This consent is bound to a particular purpose. A second ground for the processing of personal data is in order to fulfil the requirements of a contract, as specified in Article 6, Paragraph 1(b) of the GDPR. However, this clause must be understood to include the initiation of a commercial relationship with the corresponding data processing. This ground applies to ChartMogul Ltd, in the case that the user uses our contact form or contacts our Success or Sales team using any other means to obtain an non-binding quotation. Article 6, Paragraph 1© of the GDPR permits the processing of personal data where a legal requirement to do so exists. Article 6, paragraph 1(d) permits the processing of personal data in exceptional circumstances, where doing so is necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject. This ground is relevant to ChartMogul Ltd’s data processing, where ChartMogul Ltd, or at a ChartMogul Ltd event, may have to provide personal data to emergency services - such as name, contact details or health insurance - in order to prevent or treat an injury or other damage to health. It is also possible that personal data will be processed on the basis of Article 6, paragraph 1(f) of the GDPR. This is the so-called “legitimate interests” ground, which is interpreted with reference to Recital 47 of the GDPR. The GDPR treats this ground in the sense of a “fallback ground”, which only applies where no other previously listed lawful ground for processing does. When this ground is relied upon, an assessment must carefully weigh the legitimate interests of the data subject against the legitimate interests of the data controller.

## Your Rights

You have the following rights concerning your personal data:

  * The right to access your personal data

  * The right to correct or delete your personal data

  * The right to restrict processing of your personal data

  * The right to object to the processing of your personal data

  * The right to data portability

  * The right to confirm whether your personal data is being processed or not.

If you have given your consent to the processing of your personal data, you can withdraw this consent at any time. Such a withdrawal of consent will only affect the processing of your data after it is given.

Should we continue to process your personal data because we assess our legitimate interests to do so outweigh your legitimate interests (per Article 6, paragraph 1(f) of the GDPR) you may object to this processing. This is only applicable in the case where the processing of personal data is not required in order for us to fulfil a contract with you. To exercise such an objection, we request that you detail the grounds based on which we should no longer process your personal data. We will check the details of your circumstances based on the grounds you provide, and either stop processing your personal data, or detail to you the legal basis on which we continue to process your personal data.

Additionally, you always have the right to make a complaint to the relevant authorities regarding our processing of your personal data.

## How you can exercise your rights

Should you wish to exercise any of these rights, you will need to provide proof of identification that you are the person to whom the data relates. The data you will receive includes data we have related to you, the source of that data, the recipients, or types of recipients to whom the data was transferred, and the purposes for which the data was stored. To exercise these rights, please contact our data protection officer named in the beginning of this document.

**Updated:** Jan 15, 2019
